# Felix Sargent

San Francisco, CA felix.sargent@gmail.com - 415-860-6970 - https://felixsargent.com

#### Profile

I'm Felix Sargent, an experienced Engineering manager. Since working at Rackspace as a Software Engineer, I have focused on managing and growing productive, highly-collaborative teams. I believe teams work best when they feel safe, and are well equipped for their challenging work.

I specialize in engineering management around platform infrastructure, developer tools, and product backends. I code in Javascript/TypeScript and Python, but I am comfortable leading a team in any language.

## Experience

#### Head of Engineering @ RecruitBot

#### December 2022 - Current

**Company Overview:** RecruitBot is an innovative platform revolutionizing recruitment across various industries, positioned as a competitive alternative to LinkedIn Recruiter. With a vast, independently sourced candidate pool of over 650 million, RecruitBot offers unique integration capabilities with email platforms like Google Apps Suite and Office 365 for seamless drip outreach campaigns. This transparent approach, combined with a machine learning algorithm that refines candidate searches based on recruiter ratings, makes RecruitBot a leader in intelligent recruitment solutions.

- Led the development and deployment of a complex software platform, coordinating a team skilled in Scala Play, Django Python, and React.
- Migrated the team to CI/CD using GitHub actions, integrating testing and code reviews for improved operational efficiency.
- Upgraded the platform infrastructure from a single Docker setup to a modular, Kubernetes-compatible environment, bolstering scalability and testing capabilities.
- Revamped the development process by adopting Agile methodologies, fostering a more inclusive and productive team environment, and shifted project management to Linear.app for enhanced efficiency.
- Implemented tasked based scheduling using Celery

## Sr. Engineering Manager @ <u>Truework</u>

#### Oct 2021 - Oct 2022

- Managed the Interfaces (FE App, API, TrueworkJS Widget (like Plaid), <u>Encompass</u> Integration) and Infrastructure teams (Django Python BE, TypeScript React FE)
- Hired 10 engineers and 3 interns. Directly managed 11 individual contributors
- Led the "API First" strategic initiative to create a first-class external developer experience
- Renegotiated contracts with Optimizely, Stoplight and Segment to keep costs lean as we expanded the team
- Revamped Front End and Backend recruiting, interviews structure, and hiring processes
- Transitioned a hard-working but unstructured team to use modern agile processes
- Coached underperforming team members up and through promotion

## Sr. Engineering Manager, University @ Atlassian

#### May 2020 - Oct 2021

- Technical Architect of <u>Atlassian University</u>, Atlassian's customer education platform (<u>Intellum</u>)
- Performed market research on the e-learning space, working with vendors and gathering detailed requirements to migrate from legacy systems to a new vendor
- Worked to a hard deadline to migrate existing learning data to our new platform, developing integrations with Atlassian's existing system
- When needed, I dived into the code (Python, with Pandas and API integrations)
- Engineering Manager for the Training for Jira marketplace addon
- Managed a team of contractors to deliver the Training for Jira marketplace add-on.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to migrate a legacy project to a new system. Used analytics to prioritize work, and liaised with multiple third
  parties.

## Director of Engineering, Campaigns & API Usability @ MediaMath

#### November 2016 - April 2020

- Managed 15 Engineers over two teams (Perl, NodeJS, Python)
- Supported the team's migration to CI/CD, reducing test and deployment time from days to minutes and reducing server costs for QA environments by 85%
- Facilitated the migration of authentication services to OAuth across the platform, enabling MFA, and improving security and customer experience
- Advocated for and implemented <u>Feature Flagging</u> platform wide
- Oversaw the transformation of the MediaMath API portal, transforming REST API customer experience with a fanatically positive response

• Implemented Open Source license compliance regulatory schemes with <u>Fossa.io</u> enabling the close of a multi-million-dollar credit facility from Goldman Sachs

### VP of Product @ GovOS (SeamlessDocs)

#### November 2015 - November 2016

- Led the product team with a philosophy of servant leadership to encourage discussion, healthy debate, and clear communication
- Created product strategy and worked with CEO and VP Eng. to set the road map to replace unreliable legacy systems (PHP -> Scala, JS/React)
- Managed recruiting and hiring for the Engineering team, scaling from 3 to 15 engineers
- Re-established trust between engineering and sales teams by establishing consistency, stabilizing the platform, and getting bugs closed
- Developed process for the account management team to triage and prioritize customer issues bringing median resolution time down by 80%, and increasing customer NPS scores by 60%
- Conducted extensive user research with government officials to refine product features and specifications
- Re-negotiated contractual obligations with customers to reduce commitments, and align engineering road map with company direction

#### Sr. Product Manager, <u>Vault</u> @ <u>Bloomberg</u>

#### October 2014 - November 2015

- Product owner for Bloomberg Vault Surveillance, the communications monitoring and auditing tool for the Bloomberg Terminal (MCMP, BVTP)
- Implemented technology and policies to capture communications to prevent Market Abuse, Insider Trading, Harassment, and Data Loss
- Coordinated a team working on the latest and greatest technology stack including Scala, Play, Accumulo, & Akka running on a Mesos infrastructure
- Worked with Compliance and Security Officers to ensure the data integrity of our clients, and the Bloomberg Terminal

#### Engineer / Product Manager@ Rackspace

#### August 2011 - October 2014

- Product owner for <u>Rackspace Autoscale</u> (Python, Twisted)
- Initially an Engineer on the Autoscale team, and was promoted to Technical PM
- Defined the product strategy, roadmap, user stories, KPIs, and priorities
- Product owner for Repose (Java), an API Middleware Platform
- Repose handles Authentication (Openstack Keystone), Security, Rate Limiting, and Content Normalization for nearly all Rackspace APIs
- Presented Repose, the Openstack API Filter at OpenStack 2014
- Built the office **Kegerator**

## Projects

<u>Mechanical Keyboards</u> - So many mechanical keyboards.

BARTSign - Raspberry Pi Based Transit Board

Fippi - Physical internet radio, and Air Quality Monitor

My Voice is My Passport (eg 1992 movie Sneakers) - Voice Recognition Passwords for Condo Entry

#### Volunteer Work

## Chair of the Board @ Center for Election Science

#### 2017 - 2023

A non-profit organization dedicated to improving the way we vote

- CES changed the way Fargo, ND, and St. Louis, MO elect their leaders
- Recruited new board members, coordinated strategic donors, and raised grants for the organization
- Wrote Berkeley's City Council's switch to 're-weighted range voting' adds fairness to the system (Berkeleyside)

#### Mentor @ The Product Group

#### 2015 - 2017

- Recognized with the Outstanding Product Mentor Award
- <u>Managing Technical Debt</u> (July 17, 2016)
- How to Interview a Product Manager (February 7, 2016)
- <u>Inheriting a Project</u> (July 8, 2015)

## Founded the San Francisco Brigade @ Code for America

#### 2013

- Reformed the way <u>San Francisco Citizens without bank accounts get access to financial services</u>
- Brought the City Administrative Code online

# Education

# BA, Economics @ San Francisco State University

President, Economics Students Association Treasurer, Pre-Law Society Varsity Intercollegiate Policy Debate Team

# Links

Github: <a href="https://github.com/fsargent">https://github.com/fsargent</a>
Blog: <a href="https://medium.com/@antagonist/">https://medium.com/@antagonist/</a>
LinkedIn: <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/felixsargent/">https://linkedin.com/in/felixsargent/</a>

Keybase: <a href="https://keybase.io/fsargent">https://keybase.io/fsargent</a>